Guide to the Time Inc. Printing Developments, Inc. Records 1950-1974 MS 3009-RG 22
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Printing Developments, Inc. Records
1950-1974
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 22
6.25 Linear feet in 5 record cartons
Includes business expenses ledgers and payroll books of Printing Developments, Inc., a wholly-owned subsidiary of Time Inc., that manufactured and marketed technological products and services related to printing.
Arrangement Note
Organized into two series:
Series I. Business Expenses Ledgers
Series II. Manufacturers Hanover Trust Company Ledgers
Biographical/Historical Note
Printing Developments, Inc. was a wholly-owned subsidiary of Time Inc. Established in 1950, it manufactured and marketed technological products and services related to printing developed by Time Inc.'s Springdale, Connecticut research lab.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers with the exception of restricted materials. Restricted materials include records with personally identifiable information. Restricted materials are located in boxes 875 and 876. Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Related Archival Materials Note
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Scope and Contents Note
Contains business ledgers and payroll books from the Time Inc. subsidiary Printing Developments, Inc.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Ledgers (account books); Organization files; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Corporation records; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Corporations -- History; Printing machinery and supplies -- New York (State) -- New York; Printing industry -- New York (State) -- New York; Payroll records; Printing Developments, Inc.; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- Series I. Business Expenses Ledgers, 1950-1964; 200611; 3 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
  Scope and Contents Note
  Contains Printing Developments, Inc.'s business ledgers.
  Arrangement Note
  Organized chronologically.
  - 1950, 187402 (Offsite-box 665)
  - 1951, 187403 (Offsite-box 665)
  - 1952, 187404 (Offsite-box 665)
  - 1952-1954, 187345 (Offsite-box 666)
  - 1953, 187405 (Offsite-box 665)
  - 1954, 187406 (Offsite-box 664)
  - 1955, 187344 (Offsite-box 664)
  - 1956, 187400 (Offsite-box 664)
  - 1957, 187401 (Offsite-box 664)
  - 1958, 187346 (Offsite-box 666)
  - 1964, 187407 (Offsite-box 666)
- Series II. Manufacturers Hanover Trust Company Ledgers [RESTRICTED], 1973-1974; 200612; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Contains two Deductions Registers from 1973, four Earnings Registers from 1973 and 1974, and two Quarterly Summaries from 1973 and 1974.
  Organized alphabetically.
  - Ledgers, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 875)
  - Ledgers, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 876)